

+46760813340

☑ rashed\_huawei@yahoo.com

Trångsundstorg 3, Lgh: 2004,142 60, Trångsund, Stockholm

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ nur-mohammad-rashed-071a2316/

#### EDUCATION

Professional / Vocational
Training in Front Development
EC Utbildning, Stockholm

2019 – 2021

Master's in Communication Systems (Incomplete, Thesis left)

KTH, Stockholm 2009 – 2011

Bachelor's in Computer Engineering

AIUB, Bangladesh 2002 - 2006

#### LANGUAGES

English | Fluent Swedish | Proficient Bengali | Mother tongue

# **NUR MOHAMMAD RASHED**

Front-end Developer

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Creative, passionate, and certified front-end developer with more than one and half year of professional experience as a front-end developer. Having worked with fintech startup companies I have a good understanding of the life cycle of a project. In my short working life, I have led two such projects through which my current company is providing satisfactory service to its thousands of customers. One of my strengths is finding unique and simple solutions to problems that arise while ensuring a good customer experience. I consider myself a team player who can independently find different ways to move forward.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

UX/UI, HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, React, RestAPI, ReactQuery, React Hook Form, JEST, Material UI, MySQL, .Net, Firebase, Git, TDD and Agile Methodology.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Nordfin Capital Group AB, STOCKHOLM | November 2021 – Current

- Developed a fintech website (<a href="https://mypage.nordfincapital.com/">https://mypage.nordfincapital.com/</a>) from scratch using React for the customer of Nordfin Capital and by doing so I gained a lot of practical experience and knowledge in various areas such as UX/UI, Material UI, ReactQuery, React Hook form, APIs, Implementation of various payment method (Swish), BankId login technique, and last but not least Azure deployment services.
- Currently developing two projects simultaneously for internal users of Nordfin.

# FRONT-END DEVELOPER INTERN ViaEcole, STOCKHOLM | MARCH 2021 – JUNE 2021

 Created a web-based conferencing app(screen sharing) for internal users of ViaEcole using JS,WebRTC, and Firebase.

# FRONT-END DEVELOPER INTERN SEMSOMI, STOCKHOLM | FEBRUARY 2020 – MAY 2020

 Helped to develop a fully automated AI based news app (Monok) for android system using react native.

#### **NETWORK ENGINEER**

HUAWEI TECHNOLOGIES, BANGLADESH | 2008 - 2009

- Responsible for monitoring and analyzing alarms generated by Mobile Switching Center and Base Station.
- Analyzing monthly KPI for mobile network and creating performance diagram of the network was one of my responsibilities which helped me to develop my analytical and logical thinking.

### **PROJECTS**

All my projects are available at https://github.com/nurrashed

## REFERENCES

References are provided upon request.